<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<rss version="2.0"><channel><title>Just for noting</title><link>https://blog.m157q.tw/</link><description></description><lastBuildDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 09:33:00 +0800</lastBuildDate><item><title>A Free Certificate Authority to Encrypt the Entire Web</title><link>https://blog.m157q.tw/posts/2015/11/27/a-free-certificate-authority-to-encrypt-the-entire-web/</link><description>&lt;p&gt;KKTIX URL: &lt;a href="http://ocftw.kktix.cc/events/imhp"&gt;專家講座：資訊與人權的交會&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Let's Encrypt: A Free Certificate Authority to Encrypt the Entire Web&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seth Schoen - Senior staff at Electronic Frontier Foundation  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acronyms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SSL, TLS, HTTPS, X.509, PKI, CA  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSL (Secure Sockets Layer)  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The old name for the main security layer for TCP  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLS (Transport Layer Security)  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The modern name of SSL  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Importance of TLS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still occasionally dealing with the idea that it's only needed for finalncial data.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;... more often these days, the idea that it's only needed for logins.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to articulate a stronger vision that networks are untrustworthy and commmunications need to be protected.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networks are routinely attacking us and plain HTTP offers no defense.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need security for everything on the Internet?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Just a few examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidejacking and location tracking  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrity of software downloads  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reader privacy (although size of documents is still an enormous problem)  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ex: Medical info site with searchiin function but no HTTPS connection.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content-based censorship prevention  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ad, Cookies  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protection against ad injection, tracking-header-injection and even malware injection at ISP  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Barriers to adoption&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perception that TLS is slow (especially for session establishment) or is very computationally intensive  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Difficulty integrating into some server and data center designs (like load balancing)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost and effort of obtaining and managing PKI certificates  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even a skilled person who understands PKI conceptually may take ~1 hour to get and deploy a cert... and then it may expire, or omit some vhosts.  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People say it's waste of my time and not worth it.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let's Encrypt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initially, a collaboration among EFF, University of Michigan, and Mozilla  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to create a fully automated CA to issus certificates to any site for any purpose, quickly and at no charge  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aiming to be cheaper, easier, and more secure than existing CAs  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks to partners including Akamai, Cisco, and IdenTrust, we have publicly  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cross-signing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Root CAs can and do delegate their authority to intermediate CAs - currently hundreds of named entities  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browsers then automatically trust these intermediates; end-entity certs are almost always signed by intermediates, not roots  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our CA is now cross-signed by IdenTrust; &lt;em&gt;mainstream browsers trust us today&lt;/em&gt;;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let's Encrypt concept&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clien (User's Web Server), Sever (Let's Encrypt CA)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lowest level of validation for PKIX certificates is DV (Domain Validation) - verification by the CA that the applicant controls the domain name (or a server that the domain name is pointed at)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explicitly doesn't confirm the real-world identity of the applicant  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software on web server, and the server connect to the Let's Encrypt CA.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACME (Automated Certificate Management Environment) to handle conversations about cert issuance  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client claims to control a particular name or names, and asks for a cert for them  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Server issues one or more challenges to ask the client to prove its control (and/or possibly prove control of other cryptographic keys)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client satisfies these challenges and server verifies this automatically then issues cert and sends it over  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normal users: Certificates just make browsers complain the wrong domain name or expired to users while browsing the Internet. (LOL)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;ACME&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A JSON-based protocol  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let's Encrypt status&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet Security Resarch Group (ISRG)  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We don't want people to know about what we are doing, so we think this name is good.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;DVFNI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crypto  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Convenience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We anticipate people who administer their own web servers will run something like  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;$ sudo apt-get install letsencrypt  
$ sudo letsencrypt  
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;and the client will not only obtain, but also deploy, the new cert in less than a minute.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're working on a client that will parse and write Apache and Nginx configs, and autorenew expiring certs.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache sever's config file is really hard to parse, so we made a lot of effort on it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Safety&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We care a lot about avoiding misissuance and plan to adopt technologies to stop it  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are publishing all certs in Google's Certificate Transparency system  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We're planning to prevent issuance for a domain that already has a valid cert unless the applicant can prove control of its subject key  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can also have mechanisms for domains to ask us never to issue for them  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can have records about all certificates we've issued, and people can also check the list. If we got hacked, we can easily see the compromised records.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wider integration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We'd like to be integrated on every server OS or web server and every hosting and application platform  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ACME protocol is in a standardization process at IETF and will be an open standard  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use the protocol to request certs from us without using our client software.  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can even write you own client.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contractual relationship isn't required, though we welcome new sponsors.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Help!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please join the beta test program  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill out a form with your domin names + e-mail address, then wait for e-mail confirmation  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try out our service and report client or service bugs, and optionally send us pathces.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beta certs are fully "real" and mainstream browsers accept them now  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrating our client in your favorite OS or with your favorite web server  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or other server (ESMTP, IMAP, XMPP, ...)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Packaging our client  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrating our client with your favorite hosting environment  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auditing our client or server  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing more tests  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documenting our client (man pages, FAQ, introduction, explaining PKI, what key/cert/chain are)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Client written in Python, Server written in Go.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Real-world cryptography: What could possibly go wrong?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;鄭振牟 （台大電機系副教授）  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;EasyCard 2.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CDC (自然人憑證) - Citizen Digital Certificate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;政府：「新的自然人憑證應該安全了」 「你信嗎？」 「反正我是信了。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thought&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;後半段鄭教授講有關悠遊卡跟自然人憑證的部份我沒有聽的很仔細，&lt;br /&gt;
大致上是在講之前悠遊卡出包後，教授的研究團隊有投入補救，然後推出悠遊卡 2.0。&lt;br /&gt;
然後自然人憑證的部份有講到超大質數在以 Hexadecimal 顯示時會有過度規律的問題等等。&lt;br /&gt;
然後提供了許多論文，給想瞭解的人去參考。&lt;br /&gt;
我也沒有記下來，畢竟這次來主要是想瞭解 EFF 的資訊。  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;簡單來說 Let's Encrypt 在做的事情就是讓取得憑證這件事情變得愈簡單愈好，&lt;br /&gt;
方便架站者可以很快、很方便的取得並儘量自動化設定憑證，之後便能直接使用，&lt;br /&gt;
讓架站者可以迅速地提供使用者 HTTPS 加密連線，不要使用 plaintext 的 HTTP。&lt;br /&gt;
以往因為憑證的設定需要一連串繁瑣的步驟及有些複雜的指令，讓許多架站者覺得時間成本過高，&lt;br /&gt;
而且大多數的憑證是需要購買的，Let's Encrypt 則提供免費的憑證，且只需透過簡單的指令就可以迅速設定完成。&lt;br /&gt;
總之就是希望使用者在網路上的連線資料都是加密的，而不是使用 HTTP 在網路上裸奔，容易讓有心人士取得資料。  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's Encrypt 的官方網站： &lt;a href="https://letsencrypt.org/"&gt;Let's Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
有興趣的人可以點進去瞧瞧，目前只有英文，也歡迎有興趣的人貢獻繁體中文的翻譯。&lt;br /&gt;
如果你覺得他們致力於網路安全的努力值得支持的話，也可以到官方網站的 donate 連結，小額贊助一些錢給他們。  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;從 2015/9/12 到目前都是 limited beta 測試中，採填表申請並等待的制度。&lt;br /&gt;
但從下禮拜 (12/3 Thu) 開始，進入 public beta 測試階段，&lt;br /&gt;
屆時系統會開放給任何想申請的人，無需等待回信。&lt;br /&gt;
詳細公告在此 &lt;a href="https://letsencrypt.org/2015/11/12/public-beta-timing.html"&gt;Public Beta: December 3, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
有興趣的人歡迎到時候申請來使用看看，遇到任何問題或 bug 都歡迎回報給他們。  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;順便附上他們的 Twitter： &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EFF"&gt;EFF (@EFF) | Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
可以比較快的知道一些新資訊  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最後覆蓋海報一張結束這篇文章  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Poster" src="/files/a-free-certificate-authority-to-encrypt-the-entire-web/poster.jpg" /&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</description><dc:creator xmlns:dc="http://purl.org/dc/elements/1.1/">m157q</dc:creator><pubDate>Sun, 29 Nov 2015 09:33:00 +0800</pubDate><guid isPermaLink="false">tag:blog.m157q.tw,2015-11-27:posts/2015/11/27/a-free-certificate-authority-to-encrypt-the-entire-web/</guid><category>Let's Encrypt</category><category>EFF</category><category>Speech</category></item></channel></rss>