<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8"?>
<feed xmlns="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><title>Just for noting</title><link href="https://blog.m157q.tw/" rel="alternate"></link><link href="https://blog.m157q.tw/feeds/tag.speech.atom.xml" rel="self"></link><id>https://blog.m157q.tw/</id><updated>2015-11-29T09:33:00+08:00</updated><entry><title>A Free Certificate Authority to Encrypt the Entire Web</title><link href="https://blog.m157q.tw/posts/2015/11/27/a-free-certificate-authority-to-encrypt-the-entire-web/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-11-29T09:33:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-11-29T09:33:00+08:00</updated><author><name>m157q</name></author><id>tag:blog.m157q.tw,2015-11-27:posts/2015/11/27/a-free-certificate-authority-to-encrypt-the-entire-web/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;KKTIX URL: &lt;a href="http://ocftw.kktix.cc/events/imhp"&gt;專家講座：資訊與人權的交會&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Let's Encrypt: A Free Certificate Authority to Encrypt the Entire Web&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Seth Schoen - Senior staff at Electronic Frontier Foundation  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Acronyms&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;SSL, TLS, HTTPS, X.509, PKI, CA  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SSL (Secure Sockets Layer)  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The old name for the main security layer for TCP  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;TLS (Transport Layer Security)  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The modern name of SSL  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Importance of TLS&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Still occasionally dealing with the idea that it's only needed for finalncial data.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;... more often these days, the idea that it's only needed for logins.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We need to articulate a stronger vision that networks are untrustworthy and commmunications need to be protected.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Networks are routinely attacking us and plain HTTP offers no defense.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We need security for everything on the Internet?  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Just a few examples&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Sidejacking and location tracking  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrity of software downloads  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Reader privacy (although size of documents is still an enormous problem)  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ex: Medical info site with searchiin function but no HTTPS connection.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Content-based censorship prevention  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ad, Cookies  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Protection against ad injection, tracking-header-injection and even malware injection at ISP  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Barriers to adoption&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Perception that TLS is slow (especially for session establishment) or is very computationally intensive  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Difficulty integrating into some server and data center designs (like load balancing)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Cost and effort of obtaining and managing PKI certificates  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Even a skilled person who understands PKI conceptually may take ~1 hour to get and deploy a cert... and then it may expire, or omit some vhosts.  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;People say it's waste of my time and not worth it.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let's Encrypt&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Initially, a collaboration among EFF, University of Michigan, and Mozilla  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;to create a fully automated CA to issus certificates to any site for any purpose, quickly and at no charge  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Aiming to be cheaper, easier, and more secure than existing CAs  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Thanks to partners including Akamai, Cisco, and IdenTrust, we have publicly  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Cross-signing&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Root CAs can and do delegate their authority to intermediate CAs - currently hundreds of named entities  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Browsers then automatically trust these intermediates; end-entity certs are almost always signed by intermediates, not roots  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Our CA is now cross-signed by IdenTrust; &lt;em&gt;mainstream browsers trust us today&lt;/em&gt;;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let's Encrypt concept&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Clien (User's Web Server), Sever (Let's Encrypt CA)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Lowest level of validation for PKIX certificates is DV (Domain Validation) - verification by the CA that the applicant controls the domain name (or a server that the domain name is pointed at)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Explicitly doesn't confirm the real-world identity of the applicant  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Software on web server, and the server connect to the Let's Encrypt CA.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ACME (Automated Certificate Management Environment) to handle conversations about cert issuance  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client claims to control a particular name or names, and asks for a cert for them  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Server issues one or more challenges to ask the client to prove its control (and/or possibly prove control of other cryptographic keys)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Client satisfies these challenges and server verifies this automatically then issues cert and sends it over  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Normal users: Certificates just make browsers complain the wrong domain name or expired to users while browsing the Internet. (LOL)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;ACME&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A JSON-based protocol  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Let's Encrypt status&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Internet Security Resarch Group (ISRG)  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We don't want people to know about what we are doing, so we think this name is good.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;DVFNI&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Crypto  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Convenience&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We anticipate people who administer their own web servers will run something like  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;$ sudo apt-get install letsencrypt  
$ sudo letsencrypt  
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;p&gt;and the client will not only obtain, but also deploy, the new cert in less than a minute.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We're working on a client that will parse and write Apache and Nginx configs, and autorenew expiring certs.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apache sever's config file is really hard to parse, so we made a lot of effort on it.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Safety&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We care a lot about avoiding misissuance and plan to adopt technologies to stop it  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We are publishing all certs in Google's Certificate Transparency system  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We're planning to prevent issuance for a domain that already has a valid cert unless the applicant can prove control of its subject key  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We can also have mechanisms for domains to ask us never to issue for them  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;We can have records about all certificates we've issued, and people can also check the list. If we got hacked, we can easily see the compromised records.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Wider integration&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;We'd like to be integrated on every server OS or web server and every hosting and application platform  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;The ACME protocol is in a standardization process at IETF and will be an open standard  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can use the protocol to request certs from us without using our client software.  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You can even write you own client.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Contractual relationship isn't required, though we welcome new sponsors.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Help!&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Please join the beta test program  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Fill out a form with your domin names + e-mail address, then wait for e-mail confirmation  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Try out our service and report client or service bugs, and optionally send us pathces.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Beta certs are fully "real" and mainstream browsers accept them now  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrating our client in your favorite OS or with your favorite web server  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Or other server (ESMTP, IMAP, XMPP, ...)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Packaging our client  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Integrating our client with your favorite hosting environment  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Auditing our client or server  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Writing more tests  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Documenting our client (man pages, FAQ, introduction, explaining PKI, what key/cert/chain are)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Client written in Python, Server written in Go.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Real-world cryptography: What could possibly go wrong?&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;鄭振牟 （台大電機系副教授）  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;EasyCard 2.0&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;CDC (自然人憑證) - Citizen Digital Certificate&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;政府：「新的自然人憑證應該安全了」 「你信嗎？」 「反正我是信了。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thought&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;後半段鄭教授講有關悠遊卡跟自然人憑證的部份我沒有聽的很仔細，&lt;br /&gt;
大致上是在講之前悠遊卡出包後，教授的研究團隊有投入補救，然後推出悠遊卡 2.0。&lt;br /&gt;
然後自然人憑證的部份有講到超大質數在以 Hexadecimal 顯示時會有過度規律的問題等等。&lt;br /&gt;
然後提供了許多論文，給想瞭解的人去參考。&lt;br /&gt;
我也沒有記下來，畢竟這次來主要是想瞭解 EFF 的資訊。  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;簡單來說 Let's Encrypt 在做的事情就是讓取得憑證這件事情變得愈簡單愈好，&lt;br /&gt;
方便架站者可以很快、很方便的取得並儘量自動化設定憑證，之後便能直接使用，&lt;br /&gt;
讓架站者可以迅速地提供使用者 HTTPS 加密連線，不要使用 plaintext 的 HTTP。&lt;br /&gt;
以往因為憑證的設定需要一連串繁瑣的步驟及有些複雜的指令，讓許多架站者覺得時間成本過高，&lt;br /&gt;
而且大多數的憑證是需要購買的，Let's Encrypt 則提供免費的憑證，且只需透過簡單的指令就可以迅速設定完成。&lt;br /&gt;
總之就是希望使用者在網路上的連線資料都是加密的，而不是使用 HTTP 在網路上裸奔，容易讓有心人士取得資料。  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Let's Encrypt 的官方網站： &lt;a href="https://letsencrypt.org/"&gt;Let's Encrypt&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
有興趣的人可以點進去瞧瞧，目前只有英文，也歡迎有興趣的人貢獻繁體中文的翻譯。&lt;br /&gt;
如果你覺得他們致力於網路安全的努力值得支持的話，也可以到官方網站的 donate 連結，小額贊助一些錢給他們。  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;從 2015/9/12 到目前都是 limited beta 測試中，採填表申請並等待的制度。&lt;br /&gt;
但從下禮拜 (12/3 Thu) 開始，進入 public beta 測試階段，&lt;br /&gt;
屆時系統會開放給任何想申請的人，無需等待回信。&lt;br /&gt;
詳細公告在此 &lt;a href="https://letsencrypt.org/2015/11/12/public-beta-timing.html"&gt;Public Beta: December 3, 2015&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
有興趣的人歡迎到時候申請來使用看看，遇到任何問題或 bug 都歡迎回報給他們。  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;順便附上他們的 Twitter： &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/EFF"&gt;EFF (@EFF) | Twitter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
可以比較快的知道一些新資訊  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;最後覆蓋海報一張結束這篇文章  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img alt="Poster" src="/files/a-free-certificate-authority-to-encrypt-the-entire-web/poster.jpg" /&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Let's Encrypt"></category><category term="EFF"></category><category term="Speech"></category></entry><entry><title>Technology Entrepreneurship Week 5</title><link href="https://blog.m157q.tw/posts/2015/03/24/technology-entrepreneurship-week-5/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-03-24T16:27:20+08:00</published><updated>2015-03-24T16:27:20+08:00</updated><author><name>m157q</name></author><id>tag:blog.m157q.tw,2015-03-24:posts/2015/03/24/technology-entrepreneurship-week-5/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;2015/03/24&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Information about the speech&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Title: Volunteer Entrepreneur to Global Entrepreneur&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Speaker: Hank CY Huang / 黃經堯, National Chiao Tung University&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Professor, Department of Electronics Engineering in NCTU&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Director, NCTU Venture Lab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Introduction&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/myqblinks/qmote-the-water-resistant-internet-remote-for-smar"&gt;Qmote: The Water-Resistant Internet Remote for Smartphones by Qblinks — Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.kickstarter.com/projects/1411851239/gomore-stamina-sensor-the-athletes-fuel-gauge-moni-0"&gt;GoMore Stamina Sensor - The Athlete’s Wearable Fuel Gauge by GoMore — Kickstarter&lt;/a&gt;&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.gomore.me/"&gt;Gomore&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Contents&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Born to be Entrepreneur?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Actually... You are not sure until you try!!&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It is the Attitude / Characteristics&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;If not following someone's steps&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Passion&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;No more regular schedule&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Open-minded&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Listen to advices&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Ownership / Responsibility&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Remember, you are the founder&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Be brave to solve a bigger program&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Solving a problem that really matters&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;To be Successful, you also need&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;A team with good intention&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Innovation Eco-system&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;With Professional treatment&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good mentors&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Can be your potential business partners&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Good Investors (angels + series investment)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;For Investment (no mercy) - Business is business&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You need to be clear of your value proposition (tough one)&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to find (or share with) your business partners&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Technology, in most cases, takes only &amp;lt; 20% credit for the success&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Why we will invest you? Are you aware of &amp;gt; 90% failure rate in startups?&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Higher failure rates if just student-only teams&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;NCTU&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Venture Lab&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Co-working space&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Accelerator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Incubator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Asia Pacific Accelerator&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Suggestions for Entrepreneur&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Identify a Suitable Innovation Environment to attend&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Participate as Volunteer Entrepreneur if no business idea&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn from startups and be parts of innovation eco-system&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Learn to be Entrepreneur if a team can be identified and enjoy the process&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Act as Global Entrepreneur by exploring global business opportunities and network.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;"If u wanna give advices, be successful first, or your opinion is useless because it's not working anywhere."&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h1&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At first, I thought he was going to talk about those two projects on Kickstarter because he said these two projects both are his students' projects. But, he just mentioned about them without any detials further then started to talk about those Contents and Suggestions for Entrepreneur above which I think all of those things he talked about actually can be found in most of books related to the entrepreneurship in the bookstores. Although I don't think I've learned something new, I can accept that because you know... this kind of speech always need to have such contents.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;But, he showed about 5 associations in the NCTU which are helping students about their startup company or entrepreneurship in his slides, I thought he was going to talk about the details how these associations in campus will help students to make their startup dreams come ture or some kind of promote students to join these associations or make some introductions about these associations for letting students know more about them. But I was wrong, just more rules and suggestions from books.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;At last in this speech, the speaker said something like “If u wanna give advices, u need to be successful first, or your opinion is useless because it's not working anywhere.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It just made me kind of angry and don't want to ask any questions because I am “not qualified to give some advices” in his opinion anyway. If I am already a successful entrepreneur, why did I take a course called “Technology Entrepreneurship” which is supposed to teach you about how to become an entrepreneur? It's really ridiculous for me to heard about this.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was going to ask him about:  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why you just kept talking about those things in the books? I wanna learn more about what would student entrepreneurs encounter in their startup business and how you help those students with their startup based on your experience, because I think those real experience is more valuable for us not those things in books you just kept talking in this speech.”  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;“Why you kept talking about that we NCTU students is better than NTU students and know more about how to cooperate with other people without giving any improvement? As myself experience, I have some NTU friends who really know how to cooperate with their teammates. Also, I think NTU is a better place for students to build a startup because there are more and diversified departments in NTU while most of departments in NCTU are all science-related.”&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="Entrepreneurship"></category><category term="speech"></category></entry><entry><title>GitHub Talk - Advanced Git and CI in NCTU</title><link href="https://blog.m157q.tw/posts/2015/03/20/github-talk-advanced-git-and-ci-in-nctu/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-27T12:31:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-10-27T12:31:00+08:00</updated><author><name>m157q</name></author><id>tag:blog.m157q.tw,2015-03-20:posts/2015/03/20/github-talk-advanced-git-and-ci-in-nctu/</id><summary type="html">&lt;h2&gt;Look into .git directory&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;$ git init foo  
$ &lt;span class="nb"&gt;cd&lt;/span&gt; foo  
$ tree  
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;.  
├── HEAD  
├── config  
├── description  
├── hooks  
│   ├── applypatch-msg.sample  
│   ├── commit-msg.sample  
│   ├── post-update.sample  
│   ├── pre-applypatch.sample  
│   ├── pre-commit.sample  
│   ├── pre-push.sample  
│   ├── pre-rebase.sample  
│   ├── prepare-commit-msg.sample  
│   └── update.sample  
├── info  
│   └── exclude  
├── objects  
│   ├── info  
│   └── pack  
└── refs  
    ├── heads  
    └── tags  
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;refs  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;HEAD, tag, branch  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;objects  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blob, tree, commit  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blob  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;type, bytes, content of blob  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;ex: &lt;code&gt;blob 13hello,world&lt;/code&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tree  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;main file directory for the project  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tree: point to the next tree object  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blob: ref name for blob object (one for every related object files for this tree)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;commit  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;parent: point to the last commit  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;message: commit message  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;store files for git  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;SHA1 hash  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Compressed  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;commit action will add a commit object and tree object into the objects  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tree objects have filenames for blob objects  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;blob files which have exactly same content will be stored as the same hash not only in the same project but also among all users.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Branch&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;branch just store the hash of the newest commit for that branch  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h3&gt;Tag&lt;/h3&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;regular tags do not have hash value  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;be stored in refs/tags  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;just a text file contain the commit object hash  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;annotated tag  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;code&gt;git tag -a $tag_name&lt;/code&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;tagger, annotation  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;has a hash value  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Webhook&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;use &lt;a href="http://requestb.in/"&gt;http://requestb.in/&lt;/a&gt; as payload url in github, so every time there's a event github will send event message to the payload url.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Travis CI  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/muan/emoji"&gt;https://github.com/muan/emoji&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Misc&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;if you delete tree objects manually, &lt;code&gt;git fsck&lt;/code&gt; will tell you what happened.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Git does not support empty directory  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;.gitkeep  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Every files in Git are treated as binary, so the blob file is not just a plaintext file  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git clone won't clone unreferenced files in default, but you can specify that.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;git push/pull won't do anything about unreferenced files  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;$ watch -n .1 tree  
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Git commands&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;git ls-tree  
git ls-tree HEAD  

git fsck  

git show &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$tag_name&lt;/span&gt; --pretty&lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt;raw&lt;span class="sb"&gt;`&lt;/span&gt;  

git rebase &lt;span class="nv"&gt;$branch&lt;/span&gt;  

git reflog  
// use reflog to get the &lt;span class="nb"&gt;hash&lt;/span&gt; or &lt;span class="nb"&gt;alias&lt;/span&gt; and use git reset to undo your actions  

git gc  
// delete useless files &lt;span class="o"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;unreferenced files&lt;span class="o"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; after &lt;span class="m"&gt;90&lt;/span&gt; days when someone &lt;span class="k"&gt;do&lt;/span&gt; the action  
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://github.com/muan/emoji/pull/132"&gt;Example at NCTU by johndbritton · Pull Request #132 · muan/emoji · GitHub&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Thoughts&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;雖然內容大部份在 GitBook 都有&lt;br /&gt;
不過真的覺得 &lt;a href="https://github.com/johndbritton"&gt;Mr.Britton&lt;/a&gt; 真的講解得蠻清楚的&lt;br /&gt;
比較理解 .git folder 裡面的東西是在做什麼用的&lt;br /&gt;
CI 的部分只有提到 Travis CI 在 GitHub 上面的 Webhook&lt;br /&gt;
然後 show 一下 GitHub Repo 綁 Traivs CI 後&lt;br /&gt;
在 PR 的時候會幫忙跑測試&lt;br /&gt;
原本以為會介紹一下 Travis CI 大概要怎麼用&lt;br /&gt;
看來得自己找時間研究一下了  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;然後今天又拿到 Octocat 的新貼紙啦&lt;br /&gt;
&lt;img alt="Octocat" src="/files/github-talk-advanced-git-and-ci-in-nctu/octocat.jpg" /&gt;&lt;br /&gt;
感謝 &lt;a href="https://github.com/muan"&gt;muan&lt;/a&gt; 的這則 Twitter &lt;a href="https://twitter.com/muanchiou/status/571684266490265601"&gt;訊息&lt;/a&gt; 才有機會在交大聽到這場 Talk&lt;br /&gt;
原來 &lt;a href="https://github.com/muan/emoji"&gt;https://github.com/muan/emoji&lt;/a&gt; 是她的 Repo&lt;br /&gt;
GitHub 上越來越多 emoji 了XDD  &lt;/p&gt;</summary><category term="Thought"></category><category term="Git"></category><category term="GitHub"></category><category term="Speech"></category></entry><entry><title>那些年，我們一起上的 BBS: 洪任諭(PCMan) 於 TEDxNCTU 2013</title><link href="https://blog.m157q.tw/posts/2014/01/14/pcman-speech-at-tedxnctu-2013/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-26T13:19:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-10-26T13:19:00+08:00</updated><author><name>m157q</name></author><id>tag:blog.m157q.tw,2014-01-14:posts/2014/01/14/pcman-speech-at-tedxnctu-2013/</id><summary type="html">&lt;p&gt;PCMan 2013/11/30 在新竹交通大學的演講  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;影片&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;iframe width="560" height="315" src="//www.youtube.com/embed/-tYj8QmyiCc" frameborder="0" allowfullscreen&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;

&lt;h2&gt;逐字稿&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;a href="https://hackpad.com/-BBS--BqLE55Op9Lg"&gt;那些年，我們一起上的 BBS - 逐字稿: - hackpad.com&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;以下是我自己打的一些節錄，個人有稍微修改一些字詞，應該不致影響語意。  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;跟教育有關的部份真的是是心有戚戚焉啊...  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「你知道素人跟專家最大的不同在哪裡嗎？&lt;br /&gt;
素人什麼都不會、什麼都不懂、什麼都沒有經驗&lt;br /&gt;
但是這並不是缺點，正因為素人什麼都不知道，&lt;br /&gt;
所以不知道有什麼困難，所以不會害怕困難&lt;br /&gt;
因為不知道要怕什麼，所以也什麼都不會怕，&lt;br /&gt;
所以不知不覺就把一件事給做完了&lt;br /&gt;
這是我在開發 PCMan 的時候所學到的」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「很多時候，問題不是我們學的東西不夠，而是我們學的東西太多了。&lt;br /&gt;
你受到太多的訓練，你受到太多的框架侷限。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「學校教育的問題是，把太多的東西一次全部倒給你，然後分散在幾次期中考就考掉了。&lt;br /&gt;
學完這些東西以後，你一定會有個問題，我學這些東西要幹嘛？&lt;br /&gt;
我自己的學習方式是反過來的，我是先有問題，然後自己去找問題的答案。&lt;br /&gt;
最後也許我們學到的是一樣的東西，但是我的過程充滿樂趣，而你的卻會是充滿艱辛。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「就好像你不會把整本英文字典都讀完才開始用英文，&lt;br /&gt;
你也不會把地圖全部背好了然後才出門，&lt;br /&gt;
你一定是遇到不會的，然後才去找答案，這其實是我們人類的本能，&lt;br /&gt;
可是我們的教育系統是反過來的，所以你要自己再把它顛倒回來。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「光是只有動機是不夠的，不需要等你會了這個東西才去做，&lt;br /&gt;
因為世界上並沒有完美的的計畫，你可能計畫很久，然後怎麼想都有漏洞，&lt;br /&gt;
所以想到最後都沒有動手。其實，有些事是你做了之後才知道問題在哪裡的。&lt;br /&gt;
所以，稍微會一點就可以了，遇到不會的再查就好。&lt;br /&gt;
問題會一個一個慢慢的克服，我自己就是這樣走過來的。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「學校其實還有另外一個問題，&lt;br /&gt;
就是大家都使用一樣的方法教學，教你一樣的東西，然後用一樣的方法評量。&lt;br /&gt;
而學生也只有分兩種，及格跟不及格。&lt;br /&gt;
不會有人在意你的個人特色和你到底會什麼東西，反正這套教材就塞給你了。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「我們常常會笑韓國人喜歡整型，&lt;br /&gt;
不過，我問大家一個問題：&lt;br /&gt;
『你走在路上，看見整條街的人鼻子都一樣比較嚴重？還是腦子都一樣比較嚴重？』」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「你會想要怎樣與眾不同，不過這是個『假議題』。&lt;br /&gt;
其實從你在出生的那一刻起，你就跟別人不一樣了，你就與眾不同了，&lt;br /&gt;
只是我們在長大的過程中慢慢忘記了，所以今天把它想起來吧。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「如果你有什麼想做但是沒有做的事，就動手去做吧，&lt;br /&gt;
其實沒有這麼困難，最困難的就是動手去做而已。&lt;br /&gt;
做的過程中遇到困難的話，再一個一個慢慢去查資料，其實你會克服的。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「每個人都有一些他特別的地方，只是你要去把它找出來，&lt;br /&gt;
我們其實不需要兩千三百萬個考試第一名的人嘛，每個人應該有他自己的特色。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「我在醫院每個月都會送走一些人，其中有一些是大老闆、有些人是總經理，&lt;br /&gt;
有一些甚至年紀比我小，他們最後散盡家財，可是連一個月的時間都買不到，&lt;br /&gt;
我相信他們在閉上眼睛之前，一定有一些事是想做但是沒有做的，&lt;br /&gt;
所以我後來有什麼想做的事，我就會不顧一切的去做，當然有時候還是會考慮一下。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「有些事一開始看似很難，但其實你實際去做以後就會覺得沒有這麼難了。&lt;br /&gt;
這其實就很像溫水煮青蛙，最困難的步驟其實是抓青蛙，你只要把青蛙丟進去，&lt;br /&gt;
剩下的其實就是時間的問題了，所以不要害怕跨出第一步。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「回想一下，你有沒有什麼一直想做，但沒有去做的事，&lt;br /&gt;
如果有的話，不要讓那些事等你太久。&lt;br /&gt;
而且事實上，能力不夠並不是問題。因為不會可以學，做了就會了。&lt;br /&gt;
所以很多事其實是需要你動手去做，而且是現在去做。&lt;br /&gt;
因為人生其實真的沒有那麼長。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「如果你什麼都不會，你不用為此受到侷限。&lt;br /&gt;
因為你不是專家，所以你可以跳脫框架，你的思考不會受到傳統的規範，&lt;br /&gt;
有時候反而可以有所突破。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;p&gt;「不管你喜不喜歡現在的工作和職業，&lt;br /&gt;
保有一個自己的興趣、發展自己的特色是很重要的，&lt;br /&gt;
如果你有自己的興趣的話，希望你不要放棄它，&lt;br /&gt;
永遠不要放棄一個讓自己與眾不同的機會，永遠。」  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h2&gt;Reference&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://gist.github.com/hychen/8389441"&gt;hychen 在 gist 上放的逐字稿&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="PCMan"></category><category term="TEDxNCTU"></category><category term="Speech"></category></entry><entry><title>資訊工程研討 - 台灣資訊與軟體產業未來之發展與機會</title><link href="https://blog.m157q.tw/posts/2013/11/05/computer-science-seminars-the-development-and-opportunities-about-the-it-in-taiwan/" rel="alternate"></link><published>2015-10-26T15:17:00+08:00</published><updated>2015-10-26T15:17:00+08:00</updated><author><name>m157q</name></author><id>tag:blog.m157q.tw,2013-11-05:posts/2013/11/05/computer-science-seminars-the-development-and-opportunities-about-the-it-in-taiwan/</id><summary type="html">&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;講題  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;台灣資訊與軟體產業未來之發展與機會  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;演講者  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;劉念臻博士(台灣微軟開發工具暨平台推廣處總經理)  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;上官林傑  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;劉念臻博士&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Background  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;全球 IT 軟體服務支出穩定成長  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;台灣仍停滯在硬體購置階段  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;台灣對於 IT 軟體服務業投資明顯不足  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;台灣的軟體發展是個 tough business  &lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Missed schedule  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Unmanageable  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Over Budget  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Poor Quality  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Complexity  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Project failures  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;推薦閱讀： The mythical man-mouth&lt;br /&gt;
"No Silver Bullet" - in Software Engineering  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;US$250 Billion/Year on software development in US with 175,000 projects.  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Software development is not an easy thing.  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;近年來政府開始轉變  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;張善政主委將台灣政府的資訊服務採購從低價標改成最有利標，避免因低價搶標影響軟體品質。  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;政府採購的優先順序採「先軟後硬」  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Smart Device App + Cloud == 發展應用軟體的新契機  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;障礙在於商業模式，而非技術。光有技術而商業模式不變是沒有用的。  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;營收的改變  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;通路的衝突  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;內部的變革  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Windows App APP+Cloud 36 hr Hackathon  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;台灣軟體產業最需要的大環境  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;與硬體產業同樣的關注與認知  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;重視軟體/服務價值的國內市場  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;技術以外的關鍵要素:商業模式/行銷/國際化  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;軟體人才匯集的環境  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;學校軟體人才的培育  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;hr /&gt;
&lt;h4&gt;上官林傑&lt;/h4&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;AGENDA  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;趨勢會變，軟體本質不變  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;用心生活，解決真實的問題  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;追尋熱情，把事情做好  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;如果你有技術可以改善問題，卻不知道這個世界上有哪些問題必須解決，你就無法發揮你的價值。  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;醫生和律師利用資訊不對等創造他們的價值 (XDDDD  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;軟體工程師的價值是在於創造出實用價值高的軟體，而不是精通於使用那些軟體。  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;趨勢與流行  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2006 - 我會寫 web2.0 我好潮  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2009 - 我會寫 facebook App 我好潮  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2011 - 我會寫 mobile App 我好潮  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;2013 - 我會寫 JavaScript (HTML5, NodeJS) 我好潮  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;軟體開發的本質沒有改變  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;在不同的平台，寫出可執行的程式  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;程式語言或 framework 只是工具  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;好的資料結構、演算法、系統設計依然重要  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;演算法的重要性 - 你如何開平方根? SQRT(N)  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://en.wikipedia.org/wiki/Fast_inverse_square_root"&gt;Fast_inverse_square_root&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;二分逼近法  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;div class="highlight"&gt;&lt;pre&gt;&lt;span&gt;&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;left&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;right&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mi"&gt;0&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;,&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;  
&lt;span class="n"&gt;mid&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;left&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mf"&gt;2.0&lt;/span&gt;  
&lt;span class="k"&gt;while&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="bp"&gt;True&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;  
            &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mid&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;*&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mid&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;gt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;n&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;  
                &lt;span class="n"&gt;right&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mid&lt;/span&gt;  
            &lt;span class="k"&gt;else&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;  
                &lt;span class="n"&gt;left&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mid&lt;/span&gt;  
            &lt;span class="n"&gt;prev&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mid&lt;/span&gt;  
            &lt;span class="n"&gt;mid&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;=&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;left&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;+&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;right&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;/&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mf"&gt;2.0&lt;/span&gt;  
            &lt;span class="k"&gt;if&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="nb"&gt;abs&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;(&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="n"&gt;mid&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;-&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;prev&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;)&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="o"&gt;&amp;lt;&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="mf"&gt;1e-6&lt;/span&gt;&lt;span class="p"&gt;:&lt;/span&gt;  
                &lt;span class="k"&gt;break&lt;/span&gt;  
  &lt;span class="k"&gt;return&lt;/span&gt; &lt;span class="n"&gt;mid&lt;/span&gt;  
&lt;/pre&gt;&lt;/div&gt;


&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;牛頓法  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;快速牛頓法  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;努力解決生活中真實的問題  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Windows: 讓電腦能輕易為人們使用  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Google: 整理世界上的訊息，讓人們快速搜尋  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Yahoo!: 妥善編輯整理各種新聞媒體訊息  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Facebook: 與你的朋友保持聯繫  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Apple: 提供人們簡單而一致的使用體驗  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;無名小站: 提供正妹放自拍照、並且快速傳播的平台  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;You:  ???  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;網路學習  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://www.coursera.org/"&gt;Coursera&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.w3schools.com/"&gt;W3Schools&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="https://developers.google.com/"&gt;Google Developers&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;&lt;a href="http://www.wolframalpha.com/"&gt;WolframAlpha&lt;/a&gt;  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;
&lt;p&gt;做你有興趣的事情  &lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;不要輕視在學校裡面要學的東西，這些都是未來打造你的作品的基礎。  &lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</summary><category term="Microsoft"></category><category term="speech"></category></entry></feed>